a
..
job done for you.
為你完成工作。
Why bother with grid.
為什麼要使用網格？
Grid can do things that flexbox can't and I think actually if you simplify grid down
網格可以做到 flexbox 做不到的事情，而且我認為如果將網格簡化
and start using it in very simple ways.
並開始以非常簡單的方式使用它。
It can actually be easier to use and learn
它實際上比
than Flexbox can, and that's why I want to look at
這就是為什麼我想看看
how we can simplify Grid,
如何簡化網格、
and look at the easy ways to get working with it,
並看看使用它的簡單方法、
and we're going to be doing that in this video.
我們將在本影片中進行介紹。
Hello, my friend and friends,
你好，我的朋友們、
and welcome back to yet another video.
歡迎再次觀看影片。
I'm so glad that you've come to join me once again.
我很高興你能再次加入我的行列。
And if you're new here, my name is Kevin
如果你是新來的，我叫凱文
and here at my channel, I hope you fall,
在我的頻道里，我希望你會喜歡、
madly, deeply in love with 2020 CSS.
瘋狂地、深深地愛上 2020 CSS。
And if not, fall in love with it.
如果沒有，那就愛上它吧。
I hope to at least make you a little bit less
我希望至少能讓你少一點
frustrated with it.
少一點挫敗感
And today we're doing that by exploring a topic
今天，我們就來探討一個話題
that is one of my favorite things to use with CSS,
這是我最喜歡使用的 CSS 之一、
which is CSS Grid.
CSS 網格。
In simplifying grid, I actually think there's different ways
在簡化網格的過程中，我認為有不同的方法
that we can simplify it, so I'm gonna be breaking this down
我們可以透過不同的方式來簡化它，所以我將把它分解如下
and we're gonna be examining this layout
我們將用兩種不同的方法來研究這個佈局
with two different approaches.
兩種不同的方法。
So one of them is going to be more of like
其中一種更像是
a natural starting point, I think, for grid
自然的起點，我認為，對於網格
and just understanding the very basics
和理解最基本的
of how we can simplify Grid to get the layout
我們如何簡化網格來獲得我們所需的佈局
that we want it to make for us.
我們希望它為我們做的佈局。
And then the other approach we're gonna sort of
另一種方法是
scrap what we did and take another way
廢止我們所做的，並採取另一種方法
that I really like to work today,
我很喜歡這種工作方式、
and what I'd really encourage you to do
我鼓勵大家
is watch both of them,
看這兩種方法
and see which one speaks to you a little bit more.
看看哪一種更適合你。
Some are more practical for some layouts,
有些佈局更實用、
some are more practical for other layouts,
有些對其他佈局更實用、
but for both of them,
但兩者都適用、
I think they're very nice,
我認為它們都很不錯、
simple ways to approach things.
簡單的方法。
And none of it's going to sync in,
它們都不會同步、
you might watch both of them and go,
你可能看了這兩幅畫就會覺得
they both make a lot of sense.
它們都很有道理。
Grid is easy,
網格很簡單、
and then try to use it,
然後嘗試使用它、
and you might get stuck.
你可能會卡住。
Make sure when you're learning something like this
當你學習這樣的東西時，請確保
that you're practicing it.
要多加練習。
But as much as possible
但儘可能
I'm trying to eliminate some properties,
我想去掉一些屬性、
some things that we don't need to be using
一些我們不需要用到的東西
because there's so many out there for grid,
因為有太多的網格可以用了、
I want to focus on the ones that we do need
我想把重點放在那些我們確實需要
to really understand it and on the ones
要真正理解它的屬性，以及
that we can use to simplify our life,
我們可以用來簡化生活的屬性、
especially with media queries and other things.
尤其是媒體查詢和其他東西。
All right, so for this one,
好了，就說這個吧、
I'm actually building out this layout
我實際上是在構建這個佈局
that you can see here, which is in Figma right now,
你可以在 Figma 中看到、
but this is from Front-end Mentor
但這是從 Front-end Mentor
and I'm doing it
我這樣做
just because I was trying to find a nice layout
只是因為我想找到一個不錯的佈局
that we could build that would require grid
需要網格的佈局
and this looks pretty gritty to me.
我覺得這看起來很粗糙。
So we're going to use this as our example,
因此，我們將以此為例、
but what I've actually done
但實際上我所做的
is I've actually done quite a bit of work already
實際上我已經做了很多工作
in getting things styled,
的工作、
but I haven't applied anything to do with Grid yet at all.
但我還沒有應用任何與網格有關的東西。
Now if you'd like to follow along,
現在，如果你想跟著我做的話、
the GitHub repo for this is linked down below
GitHub 軟體倉庫連結如下
and I've included the starting CSS.
我還附上了起始 CSS。
So exactly what I have here
因此，我在這裡
and this style.css will be the finished version of it.
和這個 style.css 將是它的最終版本。
So if you want to follow along
所以，如果你想跟進
or play with what I have to start with
或者從我現有的開始
you can do just that.
你就能做到這一點。
Let's jump in there.
讓我們跳進去吧。
Here I have my testimonial grid
這裡有我的推薦網格
and actually, let's just go take a quick look at my markup.
實際上，讓我們快速瀏覽一下我的標記。
And so basically, I have my main here
基本上，我在這裡將主
which I set as my testimonial grid.
我將其設定為我的推薦網格。
And then inside my Main,
然後在我的 "主 "中、
I've just put each one of these card type things
我把每個卡片型別的東西
as its own article, with a class of text of testimonial
作為自己的文章，其文字類別為推薦信
and a few other utility classes and things on there
以及其他一些實用工具類和其他東西
that aren't too important.
這些都不是很重要。
But what's really important
但真正重要的是
is that these the direct children,
的直接子類、
these articles right here.
這些文章就在這裡。
And so what I'm gonna do is come over to my style
所以，我要做的就是在我的風格中
where we have my testimonial grid.
這裡有我的推薦網格。
And I think we know what we wanna do.
我想我們知道該怎麼做了。
I have the first thing to start with Grid
我首先從網格開始
is we do need a display of Grid.
我們確實需要顯示網格。
And I won't tell you how many times
我不會告訴你有多少次
I've actually forgotten to do that.
我都忘了這麼做了。
And when you do display grid, generally speaking,
一般來說，當你顯示網格時、
nothing will really change.
什麼都不會改變。
And this is actually one of the things I like about grid
這也是我喜歡網格的原因之一
compared to Flexbox, Flexbox will work.
與 Flexbox 相比，Flexbox 可以正常工作。
It gives you the columns,
它為你提供了列、
but sometimes those columns don't do
但有時這些列並不能
what you want them to do
你想要它們做的事
and you have to finick around a little bit
你就得費點心思了
and get things to, you know,
你知道、
it can be a little bit strange
會有點奇怪
if it doesn't do exactly what you want it to early on.
如果一開始沒有完全按照你的要求去做。
Whereas with grid,
而網格技術
you do display grid, generally not much changes.
一般不會有太大變化。
Sometimes if you had did it and there's paragraphs,
有時，如果你做了網格，就會出現段落、
all of a sudden things might become double spaced
可能會突然變成雙倍行距
because with grid and with FlexX,
因為網格和 FlexX
the direct children, so the grid items
的直接子代，所以網格項
or the flex items no longer have collapsing margins.
或柔性專案不再有摺疊邊距。
So that can be a little thing that can get in your way
因此，這可能是一個會妨礙你的小問題
but we have no margins between these
但我們在這些
so absolutely nothing changes
所以絕對不會有任何變化
but we do need some spacing between them.
但我們確實需要在它們之間留出一些間距。
And this is where people will sometimes use margin
這就是人們有時會使用 margin
to create spacing or of course we have gap
來建立間距，當然我們也有間隙
and I'm going to recommend gap 100% of the time
我建議大家 100% 使用 gap
because we need vertical spacing
因為我們需要垂直間距
and we need horizontal spacing.
和水平間距。
Vertical spacing and horizontal spacing
垂直間距和水平間距
I always get those backwards.
我總是把它們弄反。
If you've been following for a while, you know that.
如果你已經關注了一段時間，你就會知道。
And because we want this spacing to all be equal everywhere
因為我們希望所有地方的間距都相等
Gap makes a lot of sense.
間距很有意義。
But in general with the Gap property,
但一般來說，有了間隙屬性
by doing it we don't get gaps on the outside
這樣做我們就不會在
of any elements and things like that.
之類的東西。
Like if you wanted to add margins
比如你想新增邊距
through a grid system of any kind,
透過任何一種網格系統、
it gets a little bit annoying
就會變得有點惱人
even if it's just columns going across
即使只是橫向列
and you don't even have rows
甚至沒有行
I'd always always always recommend Gap now
我一直一直都建議現在使用 Gap
and margins I'm using less and less and less
我現在越來越少使用邊距了
for little spacing things.
小間距。
So let's come in,
所以，讓我們進來吧、
I think it's a 1.5 rim.
我想這是 1.5 英寸的邊框。
maybe it's it too, that looks pretty good. So I'll stick with that, and we're started! We have a grid
也許也是，看起來不錯。所以我就用這個，然後我們就開始了！我們有一個網格
and we have my gap and one of the first things I'm going to say is if you are working with grid,
我想說的第一件事就是，如果你在使用網格時，
make sure that you use your dev tools. So I am going to open those and in my dev tools,
確保你使用了開發工具。所以我要開啟這些工具，在我的開發工具中、
I'm going to be bringing them off screen just so it doesn't take up too much room.
我將把它們帶離螢幕，這樣就不會佔用太多空間了。
But what I'm going to do – I'm in the accessibility tab, let's go and just go to my inspector,
但我要做的是，我在 "可訪問性 "選項卡中，讓我們轉到 "檢查器"、
Here, I have this grid on here,
在這裡，我有這個網格、
and it's a little toggle.
這是個小開關。
I am in Firefox and I like Firefoxes,
我現在用的是火狐瀏覽器，我喜歡火狐、
especially for demos because things are much bigger
尤其是演示，因為東西更大
and easier to see.
而且更容易看清。
And we're going to be looking at our line numbers
我們將檢視行號
and a few other things.
和其他一些東西。
Chrome has all of these things too,
Chrome 瀏覽器也有這些功能、
it has the area names, it has line numbers
它有區域名稱、行號
and these visualizations.
以及這些視覺化功能。
So whichever browser you're in,
因此，無論你使用哪種瀏覽器、
it works almost exactly the same.
工作原理幾乎一模一樣。
You can see your grid,
你可以看到你的網格、
you can change the color of the grid.
你可以改變網格的顏色。
So actually let's go to a darker color
實際上，讓我們換成深色
just so we can see it a bit better.
這樣我們就能看得更清楚一些。
may be something like that just wait it's something that pops or will read but something
可能是類似的東西，只是等待它的東西，彈出或將閱讀，但東西
that pops a bit on our layout and again you can do that chrome or firefox and safari actually
你可以在 Chrome 瀏覽器、火狐瀏覽器和 Safari 瀏覽器中使用
there's safari's new chrome inspector is really really good you can even there's some scrolling
還有 Safari 的新 Chrome 檢查器真的很不錯，你甚至可以看到一些滾動問題
issue sometimes you might get with overlaying grids and stuff safari's new one is surprisingly
有時你可能會遇到疊加網格之類的問題。
powerful and good that's what happens when jen simmons is on the team um so we have display
這就是簡-西蒙斯（Jen Simmons）加入團隊後的效果。
And so with a grid that's there,
因此，我們可以顯示一個網格、
we can see my gaps that are coming in now,
我們就能看到我現在正在瀏覽的內容了
and, but we, of courseoup need some columns.
當然，我們還需要一些列。
And, this is the first thing I'm gonna say,
這是我要說的第一件事
if you are setting up a grid
如果你要設定一個網格
and you're not really comfortable with using grids,
而你又不太擅長使用網格的話、
one of the hardest things to know
最難知道的事情之一
is how many columns you might need?
就是你可能需要多少列？
So I'm actually gonna come on here
所以，我要在這裡
and I'm gonna grab my pen tool,
拿起我的鋼筆工具、
not my pen tool, my pencil tool,
不是我的鋼筆工具，而是我的鉛筆工具、
which I don't know the shortcut of because I never use it.
我不知道它的快捷鍵，因為我從來不用它。
We're gonna pull that open and I always, always recommend,
我們要把它開啟，我一直都推薦你用它、
and we can't see it cause there we go.
我們看不到它，因為我們走了。
We can see it now.
現在可以看到了
Figma chooses the color of it based on the background
Figma 會根據背景選擇顏色
and I was drawing on the purple so I chose a white pencil.
我畫的是紫色 所以我選擇了白色鉛筆
So there's the container that I'm inside,
這就是我在裡面的容器、
that's my main grid,
這就是我的主網格、
and then I clearly need to have something that goes here
很明顯，我需要在這裡放置一些東西
but that does need to come into this area here,
但它確實需要進入這個區域、
so let's highlight that in white too,
所以我們也用白色突出顯示它、
so that line continues here.
讓這條線在這裡繼續。
Here's the nice easy one that goes all the way down,
這是很簡單的一條線，一直向下延伸、
like that,
就像這樣、
but look, we're looking up here,
但你看，我們在往上看、
you might go I need a big one, a small one,
你可能會說，我需要一個大的，一個小的、
and a small one but don't forget over here,
還有一個小的 但別忘了這裡
this gets split too.
這個也會裂開
So I need to split this one across like that as well
所以我也要把這個橫向分割開來
This is where it can really help you visualize
這就是它能真正幫助你想象出
how many rows and how many columns you actually need because when you're looking at a design sometimes you miss things and
你到底需要多少行多少列，因為當你在看設計圖時，有時會漏掉一些東西。
Sometimes you need three rows instead of two or six rows instead of three depending on what you need to do
有時你需要三行而不是兩行，或者六行而不是三行，這取決於你需要做什麼。
Even now I get tripped up sometimes
即使是現在，我有時也會被絆倒
And I eventually get it if I'm not drawing on top of it and this takes
如果不在上面畫圖，我最終也會明白，這需要
Three seconds to do and then it just makes it a lot easier. So I know I need 1 2 3 4 columns
三秒鐘就能完成 然後就簡單多了 所以我知道我需要 1 2 3 4 列
I also need to have two rows, but I'm not going to declare them
我還需要兩行，但我不會宣告它們
I'm going to talk more about that soon, but I'm only going to declare my columns for now. So I'm gonna say grid
我很快會詳細討論這個問題，但現在我只想宣告我的列。所以我要說網格
Template columns which is how we can declare our columns because we're setting up our template
模板列是我們宣告列的方式，因為我們正在設定模板
so it's the template columns that the items will live on so grid template columns and
因此，專案將位於模板列上，所以網格模板列和
There's one unit if you're new to grid. We'll go slowly with this
如果你是網格新手，還有一個單元。我們慢慢來
So here I'm just gonna make this a bit bigger to give myself a bit more room
在這裡，我要把它放大一點，給自己留出更多空間。
So we can see everything that I'm gonna write.
這樣我們就能看到我要寫的所有內容。
And grid template columns,
還有網格模板列、
we have to say what they're gonna be.
我們得說清楚它們是什麼。
So you could come in here and say,
所以你可以在這裡說
I have a hundred pixels.
我有一百個畫素
And I'm just gonna do one and hit save.
我就做一個，然後點選儲存。
And now I have one column that's a hundred pixels.
現在我有一列是 100 畫素的。
And then I could just put a space and do 100 pixels.
然後，我就可以在空格處輸入 100 畫素。
And now I have two columns.
現在我有兩列了。
And then I could say pixels and have three columns.
然後我可以說畫素，有三列。
Cool.
酷斃了
That works really well.
效果很好
Another one you can do is come in with percentages,
另一種方法是輸入百分比、
25%, 25 and 25%.
25%、25 和 25%。
And okay, so that's working and it might look like it's not working
好了，這樣就行得通了，看起來可能不行
But it's cos it's hiding so there we go
但這是因為它是隱藏的，所以我們走吧
we have three columns going all the way across that way and
我們有三列橫向排列
One thing we want to do is actually divide this space up equally
我們要做的一件事，就是把這個空間平均分割開來
So one we keep one way we can do that is with the Fr unit
所以，我們可以用 Fr 單元來做到這一點
So one Fr. This is my new grid only I would say new because it's been around for a while
這是我的新網格，說它新是因為它已經存在一段時間了
But it's a grid only unit
但它只是一個網格單元
which is like it sort of uses the flexbox algorithm from what I understand of it and
據我所知，它使用的是 flexbox 演算法。
It's basically a fraction. So one fraction one fraction one fraction
基本上就是一個分數。所以，一個分數一個分數一個分數
So we're saying divide all of those up equally now, you can do more with fr's than this
所以我們現在說的是把所有這些平均分，你可以用 fr 做比這更多的事情
But I find most of the time you just want nice even columns
但我發現大多數時候，你只是想要漂亮的均勻柱子
And so this is a really nice way to get it to say each one is getting an equal amount of space
因此，這是一個非常好的方法，可以讓每一列都獲得相等的空間
There is more complexity to how this works, but we're not going to dive into that
還有更復雜的工作原理，但我們不打算深入探討。
We want to keep things simple and almost every time you use it
我們希望把事情簡單化，幾乎每次使用它時
That's going to be the result that you get is three equal columns
得到的結果都是三列空間相等
Or if you did five you get five equal columns
如果是五列，則是五列相等
So on and so forth now
以此類推
I'm gonna make this guy a little bigger again because
我要再把這傢伙變大一點，因為
What happens with grid is sometimes you end up doing that or I just said five so you end up actually putting in five and
網格的情況是，有時你會這樣做，或者我剛才說了五列，所以你最後實際上是放了五列，然後呢？
Then when you want like to change this
然後當你想改變這個
It's a little frustrating or even typing it out whenever I went to fire went to fire
這是一個有點令人沮喪的，甚至打出來 每當我去火去火
It's kind of annoying and they realized a lot of the time we're gonna want equal for all of them
這有點惱人，他們意識到很多時候 我們希望所有的都一樣
so that's where we have the repeat function that we can use and
所以我們可以使用重複功能
In repeat you say how many times you want to repeat it?
在重複中，你想重複多少次？
Put a comma and then say what you want to do
輸入逗號，然後說出你想做的事
So let's put a hundred pixels again
所以，讓我們再次輸入 100 畫素
just so we can see that working.
這樣我們就能看到效果了。
And so it's repeated three columns at a hundred pixels,
這樣就以 100 畫素重複了三列、
but of course I don't want a hundred pixels.
當然，我不想要 100 畫素。
We saw that a four works.
我們看到 4 畫素就可以了。
So I can just say three and one fr
所以我可以說 3 和 1 fr
and that gives me three columns
就能得到三列
that are one ifr each.
每列一個 ifr。
Except of course I just said this to three.
當然，我剛才說的是三。
But just thinking back,
但回想一下
we actually want that to be four right?
我們實際上想要的是四列，對嗎？
There we go.
這就對了。
Because again, why is it four?
為什麼是四個？
Let's go look we have one, two, three, four columns
讓我們看看，我們有一列、兩列、三列、四列
on my layer, not three.
層，而不是三層。
That was a little silly me.
我真是太傻了。
There we go.
這就對了。
So we get my four columns going across
這樣，我的四列就橫著走了
And you'll notice I haven't set any rows yet.
你會發現我還沒有設定任何行。
And actually four now, let's bring this back to three
現在實際上是四列，讓我們把它調回三列
because it looks a little nicer for the moment.
因為現在看起來更漂亮一些。
And we'll go back to four in a second.
我們馬上再回到四列。
And I just wanna talk a little bit
我只想談談
about setting grid templates rows.
設定網格模板行。
Because I think this is one of those places
因為我覺得這是
where people add complexity that they don't need to add.
因為我認為這是人們增加複雜性的地方之一。
Because notice if I say there's three columns,
因為請注意，如果我說有三列、
my content, if I have more than three,
我的內容，如果超過三列、
so when I have more than three children in here,
所以，當我有三個以上的孩子在這裡、
like these articles, if I have more than three of them,
比如這些文章，如果我有三個以上的子欄目、
they just go Oh, I got to the third column,
它們就會 "哦，我到第三列了"、
There's no more columns in this. I'm gonna create a row and come down here. And this is where you might hear the terms
這裡沒有更多的列了。我要建立一行，然後到下面來。這就是你可能會聽到的術語
Implicit and explicit grid. So this is where I've explicitly declared three columns. So I've said there are three columns
隱式網格和顯式網格。在這裡，我明確聲明瞭三列。所以我說有三列
I haven't said how many rows there are
我還沒說有幾行
so the grid is creating new rows for me as it needs to and these are
所以網格會根據需要為我建立新行，這些行就是
Implicit rows because it's just going there's content here that needs somewhere to live
隱式行，因為這裡的內容需要有地方存放
I'm gonna make that space automatically without you telling me to do that and
不用你吩咐，我就會自動為它們留出位置，然後
and as much with the web in general,
就像一般的網頁一樣、
we're so used to like items, you know,
我們習慣了像專案這樣的東西，你知道的、
the auto height where it just grows by itself.
自動高度，它會自己生長。
We place new items,
我們放置新的專案
they stack on top of each other by default.
預設情況下會堆疊在一起。
We're very used to that idea of new things
我們非常習慣這種新事物
just sort of coming in and going
就這樣進來，然後
where they should go automatically.
它們應該自動去哪裡。
So when I can, I try not to declare grid template rows.
因此，在可能的情況下，我儘量不宣告網格模板行。
I will declare it when I need to,
如果需要，我會宣告、
when I very specific grids
當我使用非常特殊的網格
where I'm trying to do very specific things
要做一些非常特殊的事情時
that need a bit of finicking around
需要費點心思
and a bit of finessing
和一些微調
and a little bit of other stuff going on.
和其他一些事情。
But for the most part,
但大部分情況下
you can get away with grid template rows
你可以使用網格模板行
and not declaring grid template columns.
而不宣告網格模板列。
And if that's the case,
如果是這樣的話、
I strongly recommend that you do that.
我強烈建議你這樣做。
Because it just gives you a lot less overhead
因為這樣可以大大減少開銷
and a lot less to think about when you're making it,
而且在製作時也不用考慮太多、
just because you just have to worry about your rows
因為你只需擔心你的行
and everything just sort of falls into place from there.
一切就都水到渠成了。
And what I'm doing here with these explicit columns
我在這裡做的這些顯式列
as I'm saying, also how big they have to be?
就像我說的，它們必須有多大？
Whereas with those rows that it's implacently creating
而對於那些正在建立的行
or these automatically created rows,
或自動建立的行、
it's just doing what it needs to do.
它只是在做它需要做的事情。
It's matching the height of the tallest one,
它會匹配最高的那一列的高度、
basically, that's a lot like how Flexbox works.
基本上，這很像 Flexbox 的工作原理。
If you do display flex,
如果你使用的是顯示柔性框，那麼
they just all match the height of the tallest item.
它們都會匹配最高項的高度。
You can change this behavior
你可以改變這種行為
and you can get control on your auto rows
並控制自動行
or auto columns if you fall into that world.
或自動列。
But we want to keep things simple for now.
但我們現在想把事情簡單化。
So I'm not gonna get into that,
所以我就不多說了、
but it is a possibility,
但這是一種可能性、
but let's keep things as simple as we can.
但我們還是儘量把事情簡單化吧。
So every time you're gonna do a display grid,
所以，每次你要做一個顯示網格時、
you'll probably wanna set a gap on there.
你可能會想在上面設定一個間隙。
and then you're going to set up some columns.
然後再設定一些列。
Then if you need to, start worrying about more.
然後，如果有必要，就開始擔心更多。
But, we're not going to do that.
但是，我們不會那麼做。
Let's fix this.
讓我們來解決這個問題。
We go back up to four.
我們回到四樓
And let's start trying to get this layout
我們開始嘗試讓這個佈局
to work for us a little bit.
為我們工作一點點。
And so let's go look back at our layout.
讓我們回頭看看我們的佈局。
And we have this one here,
這裡有一個
and this one here,
和這個、
that need to span across two columns each.
需要分別橫跨兩列。
So let's go and create something
因此，讓我們建立一個
that can allow us to do that.
讓我們能做到這一點。
And what I really like for this type of thing,
我非常喜歡這種型別的東西、
instead of trying to find like a class,
而不是去找一個類、
a specific class for each one of those
一個特定的類
and writing it twice,
並寫兩次、
I'm going to come here,
我要到這裡來、
And I'm just going to write, a dollarspan2.
我就在這裡寫，a dollarspan2。
and I could call this just span2,
我可以把它叫做 span2、
I guess, if I wanted to.
我想，如果我願意的話。
I just like being really explicit
我只是喜歡明確地
this class should be used with grid.
這個類應該和 grid 一起使用。
So I start with grid.
所以我從 grid 開始。
It's a sort of a little naming convention,
這是一個小小的命名約定、
but you can name it however you want.
但你也可以隨心所欲地給它命名。
You might be saying, well there's no other way to span.
你可能會說，那就沒有其他方法了。
There is the multi-column-layout
我們有多列布局（multi-column-layout
that actually does have spans
實際上是有跨度的
and it did before grid even existed, I believe.
我相信在網格出現之前就有了。
But, and it's a little bit different in how that works.
但是，它的工作方式有點不同。
what we're going to do is say my grid column and even here this I guess this
我們要做的就是說我的網格列，甚至在這裡，我想這
could be grid call, call span two just in case you end up with row span two. So
可能是網格呼叫，呼叫跨度二，以防你最終使用行跨度二。所以
let's do that grid call span two and so my grid column will be you only guess
讓我們這樣做，網格呼叫跨度二，這樣我的網格列就會是你所猜測的
span two isn't that so easy? Grid column is a shorthand property and we're going
跨度二，是不是很簡單？網格列是一個速記屬性，我們將
to explore that a little bit more shortly but one nice thing is when you
但有一點很好，那就是當你
just need to throw spans on staff it just works it doesn't matter that it's a
只需將跨度加到工作人員身上，就能正常工作。
and shortly after that shorthand,
和不久之後的速記、
it puts it sort of where it should go
它會把它放在它應該去的地方
because you could actually put the span
因為你實際上可以把跨度
on the start or the end.
在開頭或結尾。
Anyway, that's going to work.
總之，這樣就可以了。
I'm gonna hit save.
我點選儲存。
So it's here, and we'll go over to my HTML.
就在這裡，我們再轉到我的 HTML。
And we're gonna add that into spots
我們要把它新增到
where you need it on my first one.
你需要的地方
So this is my first article.
這是我的第一篇文章。
Grid, call, span two.
網格，呼叫，跨度二。
If you're saying that's a long class name,
如果你覺得這個類名太長的話
it is, but that's okay.
沒錯，但沒關係。
I like longer class names
我喜歡長一點的類名
if they really explain to me what they're doing.
如果它們真的能向我解釋它們在做什麼的話。
That's fine.
沒關係。
I don't want like a GC S2 or something,
我不想要像 GC S2 之類的名字、
cause then I'll never remember that
因為那樣我永遠也記不住
and I'll never really know what it's for
而且我也不會真正知道它是做什麼用的
or if somebody else comes to my code, they don't know.
或者別人看到我的程式碼也不知道。
Whereas this, it's very explicit.
而這個，它非常明確。
If somebody were to come across this they see it.
如果有人看到這個，他們就會明白。
There's a grid and they see
有一個網格，他們會看到
these are grid columns span two, it's a super clear.
這些是網格列，跨度為 2，非常清晰。
So I like clear class names
所以我喜歡清晰的類名
that explain exactly what they're doing.
能準確解釋它們在做什麼。
So let's hit safe here and see.
所以，讓我們點選這裡看看。
Wow, look at that.
哇，看看這個。
Now there's some weird funkiness coming up over here
現在這裡出現了一些奇怪的怪異現象
because this one is now so long
因為這一條太長了
and it's mucking this up
把這個弄亂了
because remember they're stretching
因為他們在拉伸
to try and match each other's heights.
試圖匹配彼此的高度
But that's okay.
不過沒關係。
We made some nice progress.
我們取得了不錯的進展
Where the real issue is actually coming from
真正的問題在於
is this one is in the wrong spot,
就是這個位置不對
but I put it there on purpose.
但我是故意把它放在這裡的
And not on purpose
不是故意的
because of, it would actually make more sense
因為
if this was one, two, three,
如果是一 二 三
whoops, let's get that in black,
哎呀，還是用黑色吧、
three, four, five, right?
三 四 五 對吧
Cause then that would be the order I see them in here.
因為我看到的順序就是這樣的
The thing is, in this Figma design,
問題是，在這個 Figma 設計中、
we have a mobile layout too.
我們也有一個移動版面
And Janet is the third one.
珍妮特是第三個
That's the third one here.
這是第三個
I like working mobile first,
我喜歡先做移動版、
we're going to talk about the media queries in a second though,
不過，我們馬上就要討論媒體查詢了、
but right now we need to get this one over here
但現在我們需要把這個
or Ciara over here, one or the other,
或 Ciara 在這裡，二選一、
and to do that there's lots of different approaches
要做到這一點，有很多不同的方法
and different ways we could do something like that.
要做到這一點，有很多不同的方法和途徑。
This is where for me, utility classes don't quite work
對我來說，這就是實用工具類不太管用的地方
just because you're placing things in very specific spots
因為你要把東西放在非常特殊的地方
or moving things around.
或移動東西。
I just find it easier to actually target the class
我覺得更容易的做法是把類的目標鎖定在
that I want to work on.
我想做的事情。
And I could actually just give this specific one a class
實際上，我可以給這個特定的類
and target it.
並鎖定它
Cause if I look here, it's all very generic.
因為如果我看這裡，都是很普通的東西。
My classes, I have testimonial, the background colors
我的類，我有推薦信，背景顏色
and a few other things going on there
和其他一些東西
but it's all very generic classes to style this up.
但這些都是非常通用的類，用來設計風格。
So there's different ways of selecting it.
所以有不同的選擇方式。
Just for simplicity sake
只是為了簡單起見
and not wondering about creating a class for it.
而不是糾結於為它建立一個類。
I am going to use the nth child selector
我將使用第 n 個子選擇器
or alters the last child selector, I guess,
或改變最後一個子選擇器、
just because it's gonna be faster for now.
因為現在這樣會更快一些。
If you wanted to make this a little bit more plug and play,
如果你想讓它更即插即用，你可以這樣做
you could then actually give them very specific
你可以給它們賦予非常具體的
classes that could make this work,
類來實現這一功能、
and but this is my test.
但這是我的測試。
It is a testimonial, so we're gonna say
這是一個測試，所以我們要說
testimonial last child.
testimonial last child.
And because that's gonna select the last child,
因為他要選擇最後一個孩子、
let's say background red important,
比方說，背景紅色很重要、
just to see, there you go.
看看就知道了。
We can see that it's actually selecting the one
我們可以看到，它實際上選擇了一個
that we wanted to select,
我們想要選擇的那個、
So let's get rid of that.
所以我們把它去掉。
And now we can get a little bit more
現在，我們可以進一步
about placing items on the grid
在網格上放置專案
when they're not going where you want them to go.
當它們不在你想要它們去的地方時。
And this is where Line Numbers really come in.
這就是行號的真正作用所在。
And I've had my Grid Overlay on this entire time.
我的網格疊加功能一直都開著。
It's really important when you're using your Grid Overlay,
在使用網格覆蓋時，這一點非常重要、
which has changed colors on me,
它在我身上變了顏色、
this happens sometimes when things refresh
有時重新整理時會出現這種情況
even though it's still set to red here.
儘管這裡仍然設定為紅色。
Just because it makes it a bit easier
因為這樣會更容易一些
to see on top of the purple.
在紫色之上。
I'll change that back to red.
我會把它改回紅色。
But even if you're not working with it on all the time,
但即使你不是一直開著它工作、
If you're gonna touch your line numbers,
如果你要觸控你的行號，
I highly highly highly recommend
我強烈建議
that you go ahead and have this on
我強烈建議你把它開啟
because seeing the line numbers
因為看到行號
makes it so much easier to work with.
因為看到行數
And so I want it to be on my column four
因此，我希望它在我的第四欄
to my column five.
到第五欄。
And we want it from,
我們希望從
let's go look actually at the figma design.
我們來看看 figma 的設計圖。
I want it to be from the top here
我希望它從頂部開始
and go all the way down to the bottom on this side.
一直到這邊的底部。
So to be able to do that,
所以要做到這一點
let's start with the column,
讓我們從柱子開始
So we're gonna get this in the right spot. So we saw the grid column
所以我們要把它放在正確的位置。我們之前看到過網格列
Property before so I'm saying before we said span to so let's just do that for fun span to just to see that
屬性，所以我說，之前我們說的是 "span to"（跨度），所以讓我們做一下 "span to"（跨度），就知道了。
Oops, we need that and it works it goes across the two like that
哎呀，我們需要它，而且它能像這樣橫跨兩列
But in this case, I don't want to be doing a span to actually want to say start at line number four
但在這種情況下，我不想做一個跨度，實際上是想說從第四行開始
So we can actually just put in grid column four and it will start at the line four and it leaves this one empty
因此，我們可以在第四列中加入網格，這樣就可以從第四行開始，而這一行則是空的。
why is it doing that?
為什麼要這麼做？
What's happening?
發生了什麼？
So, grid column as I mentioned is a shorthand
正如我提到的，網格列是一個速記符號
and the shorthand is for grid column start
是網格列開始的簡稱
and my grid column end
和我的網格列結束
and basically if I just do a grid column like that four,
基本上，如果我只做了這樣的四列網格、
it's just putting it as a grid column start
它只是把它作為網格列的起點
and it's not putting a grid column end
而不是網格列結束
just because it doesn't even need to do that
因為它根本不需要這樣做
we don't really need a grid column end
我們並不需要網格列的末尾
but just for fun, I could put three here
但為了好玩，我可以把三放在這裡
and we could say that the grid,
我們可以說，網格、
let's do a start, grid-column start is at three
讓我們做一個起點，網格列的起點是三
and grid-column end is at five
網格列結束位置是五
and we get the same idea as the span two.
這樣我們就能得到與跨度二相同的效果。
The reason I prefer span two when I can use it
在可以使用跨度二的情況下，我更喜歡跨度二的原因是
is because here the span two class is working for this one
是因為在這裡，span 2 類適用於這一個
and it's working for this one over here.
也適用於這裡的這個。
It doesn't matter where they are
它們在哪裡並不重要
and even we're gonna end up movie this one over in a minute
甚至我們會在一分鐘內把這一個拍成電影
or where they're lining up.
或他們在哪裡排隊。
Span two is just saying it doesn't matter where you start
跨度二隻是說，你從哪裡開始並不重要
but the end,
重要的是結束
And we just wanna make sure
我們只想確保
we're spanning across two columns.
我們要跨兩列。
So this one's a little bit more versatile
因此，這種方法比鎖定在一列中
than locking in with specific line numbers.
比鎖定特定行號更靈活。
And just like before I said,
就像我之前說的
don't create rows unless you need to create rows.
除非需要建立行，否則不要建立行。
Don't start using line numbers
不要開始使用行號
unless you need to use line numbers.
除非你需要使用行號。
Start as simple as possible
開始時儘可能簡單
and add the complexity as you need to
並根據需要增加複雜性
to be able to get the layout that you need.
以獲得所需的佈局。
So first display grid, then my gap,
因此，首先顯示網格，然後是間隙、
then I set up my columns.
然後設定列。
Then I go, Oh, I need a few of these to span.
然後，我就會想，哦，我需要一些這樣的跨度。
So I make a very general generic way to span columns.
於是，我用一種非常通用的方法來跨列。
I'm not saying you're going
我不是說你要
from 1 to 3, and then oh, you're going to from 2 to 4, whatever, we need to get that
從 1 列到 3 列，然後再從 2 列到 4 列，不管怎麼說，我們需要把這
one to.
一列。
We actually, in this case, we can get rid of the end, because I don't need to worry
實際上，在這種情況下，我們可以去掉結尾，因為我不需要擔心
about that, but we need it to start at 4.
但我們需要從 4 開始。
So we need it to be here, but I also need it to move up.
所以我們需要它在這裡，但我也需要它向上移動。
I need it starting at the top.
我需要它從頂部開始。
So I'm going to come here, and then this is when I'm finally going to worry about my row.
所以我要從這裡開始，然後這是我最後要擔心的一行。
So we can do grid row, and we can do start on here.
所以我們可以做網格行，然後從這裡開始。
And where do we want it to start?
我們想從哪裡開始呢？
At the top, at 1.
從最上面的 1 開始。
Oh my goodness!
我的天吶
It's all coming together so quickly.
一切都來得太快了。
now what happened?
現在怎麼了？
Why did everything just fall into place?
為什麼一切都那麼順理成章？
Again, start simple,
還是那句話，從簡單開始、
start moving things
開始移動
and all of a sudden your layout
突然間，你的佈局
might come together more than you think.
可能會比你想象的更完美。
And so by saying grid rows start one.
所以說，網格行是一個開始。
Let's take this one off.
讓我們把這個拿掉。
It's going in the order of the DOM.
它是按照 DOM 的順序排列的。
So this is the,
所以這是
you know what, let's choose the third one here.
選擇第三個吧。
Testimonial,
推薦、
and child three,
和孩子三、
the sky, background, red, important.
天空、背景、紅色，很重要。
I just want to highlight
我只想強調
this is my third one in my dom.
這是我的第三個孩子。
So it's one, two, three.
所以是一、二、三。
The third one is going here
第三個要放在這裡
because that's just following the natural flow
因為這只是按照
that the items will go in.
的自然流程。
First column, second column, third column,
第一列、第二列、第三列、
it just goes and it goes,
它就這樣流淌著，流淌著、
oh, we're out of room, I'm gonna go down.
哦，沒地方了，我要下去了。
I'm gonna go to where this guy is.
我要去這個人所在的地方
And then we get that one
然後我們把那個
and then it sort of moves across from there.
然後從那裡開始移動
As soon as I do grid row start one,
只要我做了網格行開始之一，
I'm saying, I need you, your grid column start is four,
我就會說，我需要你，你的網格列起始位置是4、
so you're living in this box,
所以你就住在這個盒子裡、
but I also need you to start at line number one,
但我還需要你從第一行開始、
which is the very top.
也就是最頂端。
So as soon as I do that and I save that,
所以，只要我做了這些，並儲存了這些資訊、
it has to live here, which means this one can't live there.
它就必須住在這裡，這意味著這一行不能住在那裡。
So it pushes down into the next empty cell
所以它會推到下一個空格中
that it can find, and it just automatically goes there.
就會自動移到那裡。
Even though this is the third one in the DOM,
儘管這是 DOM 中的第三個、
it's grid-smart, and you can overlap.
它是網格智慧的，可以重疊。
Actually overlapping content with grid
實際上，與網格重疊的內容
is just, it's wonderful, but it won't do it by default.
重疊內容是非常棒的，但預設情況下不會這樣做。
You have to work at it a little bit
你必須花點功夫
to actually get things to overlap.
才能讓內容重疊。
So that gets pushed up, this falls down over here
所以，這個會被推上去，這個會掉下來
because that's the next empty cell
因為這是下一個空單元格
that was available to it.
它可以使用。
So awesome.
太棒了
And I guess we can turn that red off now.
我想我們現在可以把紅色關掉了。
We don't need that.
我們不需要它了。
And the last thing is we need this
最後，我們需要
to fill up all that space
來填滿這些空間
and these are stretching, they look really ugly,
這些都在拉伸，看起來很醜
but as soon as this is allowed to stretch,
但只要讓它拉伸，就可以了、
it should fix that problem.
就能解決這個問題。
So how can we do that?
那麼我們該怎麼做呢？
hopefully you've already come up with an idea or two we can come in with a grid row end and
希望你已經想出了一兩個辦法，我們可以在網格行的末端加上
There's a few options
有幾種選擇
I could choose
我可以選擇
My three because remember we have a one here my line number two here or and my line number three down here
我的三號行，因為我們在這裡有一個一號行，我的二號行在這裡，或者我的三號行在這裡
So I couldn't throw a three and then the layout is done
所以我不能選三號，這樣佈局就完成了
Or you might have said well
或者你可能會說
I can do a span and you're right you could you could they span, too
我可以做一個跨度，你是對的，你可以 你可以他們跨度，太
And then it's gonna start at the top and span across to exact same result
然後它就會從頂部開始，橫跨到完全相同的結果上
There's no difference between them. So there we go, we're spanning across the two of them that way
它們之間沒有區別。這樣，我們就可以橫跨它們兩個了
another option is to use the shorthand. So instead of writing all of this,
另一種方法是使用速記。這樣就不用寫這些了
when you use the shorthand, you do grid row, and then you're saying, where do you want it to start?
當你使用速記法時，你會寫網格行，然後你會說，你想讓它從哪裡開始？
And then where do you want it to end? So 1 over 3? we'll start at line number 1 and go 2
然後在哪裡結束？我們從第 1 行開始，然後從 2
to 3, or you could do 1 over span 2. And that will give you the exact same result.
到 3，或者你也可以從 1 到 2。這樣就能得到完全相同的結果。
and you can just in this case where you're declaring a starting row, using
在這種情況下，你可以使用
whether it's a span or whether it's something else it doesn't matter too
不管是跨度還是其他什麼，都沒有太大關係
much if you like the idea of this actually being utility class just like I
如果你想讓它成為實用工具類，就像我之前做的那樣
did before you could come in and create something like that a grid row span to
之前那樣，你就可以進來建立類似的網格行跨度來
and do a grid grow span to and use that in conjunction with a grid row Start
的網格行跨度，並將其與網格行結合使用 開始
There's the possibility with things like that
這樣就有可能
that because this is a shorthand
因為這是一種速記
it might actually get overridden
實際上可能會被覆蓋
and you can run into a little bit of finickiness.
你可能會遇到一些小麻煩。
So if I need to do a specific starting line
因此，如果我需要做一個特定的起始行
or a specific ending line or anything like that,
或特定的結束行或類似的東西、
I tend to declare it on the selector where I'm working
我傾向於在我工作的選擇器上宣告它
instead of using utility class.
而不是使用實用工具類。
But if I don't need to declare anything specific,
但如果我不需要宣告任何特定的內容、
that's where I like the utility classes
我就喜歡實用工具類
that work based on just where its natural flow is.
我喜歡實用工具類，因為它可以根據自然流向來工作。
And we're going to get to the media queries in one second
我們將在一秒鐘後進行媒體查詢
And I just want to recap a little bit
我只想回顧一下
of the simplicity of this.
的簡單性。
And I've gone over it before,
我之前已經講過了、
but first display grid because we need it.
但首先要顯示網格，因為我們需要它。
GAP, because that makes our spacing
GAP，因為它能讓我們的間距
and our life easier there,
讓我們的生活更輕鬆、
and then set up your columns.
然後設定列。
Don't set up rows unless you have to.
除非必要，否則不要設定行。
We didn't have to in this case,
在這種情況下，我們不必這樣做、
even though we did have to span multiple rows.
儘管我們確實需要跨多行。
Pretty nice and pretty neat.
非常好，非常整潔。
And I think makes things a lot easier to maintain
我覺得這樣更容易維護
and a lot easier to think about.
也更容易思考。
We can use spans,
我們可以使用跨距
just to span columns.
來跨列。
It doesn't matter where things are starting.
從哪裡開始並不重要。
And then if you need to,
如果需要的話
we can do specific things of start in this exact location
我們可以做一些特定的事情，從這個確切的位置開始
or start here and end over here and different things like that.
或者從這裡開始，在這裡結束，諸如此類。
So, always do as general as possible and as generic as possible.
所以，一定要儘可能籠統，儘可能通用。
Simplify things as much as possible
儘可能簡化
and then, when you need to get very specific,
然後，當你需要非常具體時、
then add that specificness to your grid
在網格中加入具體內容
just to get things to fall where they need to.
這樣才能讓事情按部就班地進行。
But a lot of the time, you don't even need stuff like this.
但很多時候，你甚至不需要這樣的東西。
This is really when you're getting into these weird layouts like this
真正需要的是像這樣的奇怪佈局
where things are sort of getting a little fancier.
這樣的怪異佈局時才會用到。
And next, we want our immediate queries.
接下來，我們要進行即時查詢。
So, I'm gonna open up responsive mode,
所以，我要開啟響應模式、
the shortcut is Shift-Command-M.
快捷鍵是 Shift-Command-M。
I dunno know if that's probably a Command-Shift-M.
我不知道是不是 Command-Shift-M。
I'm guessing if you're on a Mac, that is in your dev tools.
我猜如果你用的是 Mac，這應該在你的開發工具裡。
Also, I get asked a lot about this, so that's this little guy.
另外，我經常被問到這個問題，所以這就是這個小傢伙。
Uh, not this little guy, this little guy in your dev tools.
呃，不是這個小傢伙，是你開發工具裡的這個小傢伙。
And in Chrome, this exact same icon
在 Chrome 瀏覽器中，這個一模一樣的圖示
is on this side over here.
就在這邊。
So, just because I always get asked about this.
我總是被問到這個問題。
And I mentioned the nice thing with responsiveness in grid
我提到了網格響應速度的好處
So we will do an extra little stage in this
因此，我們將在此做一個額外的小階段
that wouldn't really be for this layout specifically.
這並不是專門為這個佈局設計的。
But let's fix this at the beginning.
但讓我們在一開始就解決這個問題。
And this is where I can actually leave everything I've done,
在這裡，我可以把我所做的一切都留在這裡、
except for one thing.
除了一件事。
There's a few little things we'll have to do,
我們還需要做一些小事情、
but I'm going to grab this grid template columns.
但我要抓住這個網格模板列。
I'm going to remove it from here and hit Save,
我要把它從這裡刪除，然後點選儲存、
and let's see what happens.
看看會發生什麼。
We still have a layout.
我們仍然有一個佈局。
And what I'm going to do is come here and say,
我要做的就是在這裡輸入
app media and we'll just say a min width of 40.
app media（應用媒體），並設定最小寬度為 40。
I'm guessing and let's put in my testimonial grid
我猜想，然後把我的推薦網格放進去
and we're gonna redefine my columns there.
然後重新定義我的列。
One thing you'll notice is even though,
有一點你會注意到，即使..、
actually let's just remove this
實際上，讓我們把這個
so we can see that we don't have anything.
這樣我們就能看到我們什麼都沒有。
We actually have a bit of,
實際上，我們有一點
the layout's working even though
即使
I haven't declared my columns here.
我還沒有在這裡宣告我的列。
But the columns spacing has gotten
但列的間距
a little mucked up because it's going to the autospacing
有點亂，因為它要使用自動間距
like this one.
就像這個。
You can see here we have a really narrow column,
你可以看到這裡的列非常窄、
here we have a bigger column.
這裡有一列比較大。
So that's why I do like declaring them.
這就是我喜歡宣告的原因。
The reason that it's just magically working
它之所以能神奇地工作
is because of this grid column start.
是因為網格列的起始位置。
If I turn this off,
如果我把它關掉
the whole thing falls apart.
整個系統就會崩潰。
But it's going, this has to be on the fourth column.
但它必須在第四列開始。
So that means I need to have four columns for this to work
這意味著我需要有四列才能工作
and then everything will just sort of
然後所有的東西都會
slot into those empty spaces.
插入這些空白處。
So that's why we sort of have a layout right now.
這就是我們現在有一個佈局的原因。
But what we're gonna say is,
但我們要說的是：
actually let's put it right here,
實際上，讓我們把它放在這裡、
my media query,
我的媒體查詢、
and then I'm going to grab this
然後我要抓取這個
and also put it inside the media query.
也放在媒體查詢中。
And now we have this at my large screen sizes.
現在，我們就可以在大螢幕尺寸下看到它了。
And then, I think we should change
然後，我認為我們應該更改
where that's happening at.
發生的位置。
And actually I'm going to bring this up to a 50
實際上，我要把它調到 50
cause it was getting a little bit narrow there.
因為這裡有點窄。
And we can see, there we go.
我們可以看到，就這樣。
Look at that.
看看這個
It's going and then it's working
它開始工作了
except it's not really working
但這不是真正的工作
cause these are still spanning to.
因為這些還在延伸
This would depend a little bit on your layout
這取決於你的佈局
but I think most of the time
但我認為大多數情況下
your spans are going to be happening
你的跨度會發生
once the grid is sort of more defined.
一旦網格更加明確。
and when things are kicking in.
當事情開始發生的時候。
So I'm also going to bring that utility class here.
因此，我也要在這裡引入實用工具類。
This isn't the most organized CSS at the moment,
目前這還不是最有組織的 CSS、
but just to say, we want to start without any spans,
但我想說的是，我們希望在開始時不使用任何跨度、
without any columns, anything like that.
沒有任何列之類的東西。
But I'm still using my display of grid
但我仍然在小螢幕上使用我的顯示網格
at the small screen size, because then I have my gap
的顯示方式，因為這樣我就有了間隙
and all my spacing is there.
所有的間距都在這裡。
And actually, let's just turn off
實際上，讓我們關閉
the inspector thing now.
檢查器。
So yeah, just for the purpose of having that gap,
沒錯，就是為了留出間隙、
I think that's wonderful.
我覺得這樣很好。
And then we get to our larger screen size
然後，我們進入更大的螢幕尺寸
and then we get our columns and everything falls in
然後我們得到我們的列，所有東西都落在裡面
and then we go back down that way.
然後我們再回到那個位置。
And so that works really really nicely
這樣就非常好用了
and it's just about keeping things organized
只是為了讓事情井井有條
within your media queries where you need them to be.
在你需要的地方。
There are ways of working without media queries with...
有一些方法可以在沒有媒體查詢的情況下工作...
you might see it with like a repeat autofit
你可能會看到重複自動匹配
and other things like that
之類的東西
that are actually fairly easy to use
這些方法其實很容易使用
but on a layout like this it just doesn't work
但在像這樣的佈局上，它就行不通了
and I don't want to dive into it
我不想深入研究它
because we're just adding...
因為我們只是新增...
we're keeping grid simple today.
我們今天要保持網格簡單。
Hopefully this is still keeping it very simple for you
希望這對你來說仍然非常簡單
and moving things into the media query
並將內容移入媒體查詢
Hopefully it doesn't throw you off too much there.
希望這不會讓你太失望。
But again all of this code,
但所有這些程式碼
if you want to look at it in more detail,
如果你想了解更多細節，請訪問
the GitHub repo is linked below
GitHub 程式碼庫連結如下
and you can access all the code there.
你可以訪問那裡的所有程式碼。
Now the last thing I want to talk about
最後我想說的是
that I find actually simplifies things
我發現它實際上簡化了
with grid a little bit is a way
的方法是
that I used to not want to work at all.
我以前根本不想用它。
But I find when it comes
但我發現當涉及到
to media queries and all of that,
媒體查詢和所有這些、
it makes grid just wonderful.
這讓網格變得非常棒。
And it does take a little bit more setup,
這確實需要更多的設定、
but I find it's a nice easy way
但我發現這是一種很好的簡單方法
to work with grid when you have
當你有
more complex layouts like this.
更復雜的佈局時，它是一種很好的簡便方法。
In doing this, we're also gonna explore
在此過程中，我們還要探索
a few other properties that we haven't looked at yet.
其他一些我們還沒有研究過的屬性。
And so what I'm gonna do is, I'm actually gonna come
所以，我要做的是，我實際上是要來
and I'm gonna delete all of this.
把這些全部刪除。
I'm gonna delete the media query,
我要刪除媒體查詢、
because we are gonna need it,
因為我們需要它、
but I'm gonna delete all of that.
但我會刪除所有這些。
And we're left back where we started
我們又回到了開始的地方
with our display grid at the very beginning.
一開始的顯示網格。
And this is just another approach,
這只是另一種方法、
it's why I'm breaking it sort of into two.
這就是為什麼我要把它一分為二的原因。
But it's one of my favorite ways to work with grid.
但這也是我最喜歡的網格工作方式之一。
The way we just looked at, I think,
我想，這就是我們剛才看到的方法、
is the best way to understand
是瞭解
how grid is working,
網格是如何工作的、
and the simple ways of setting up
以及設定網格的簡單方法
a nice simple grid.
網格的簡單設定方法。
This is when you need more complex layouts
當你需要更復雜的佈局時
with a little bit more happening
更復雜的佈局時
where things change a little bit more.
變化更多一些的時候。
So we're going to break away from the actual design
因此，我們將脫離實際設計
as well a little bit with this one.
在這一點上也是如此。
And what I'm going to do is actually set up
我要做的就是設定
some grid template areas.
一些網格模板區域。
And with grid template areas,
有了網格模板區域
the syntax of it's a little weird,
它的語法有點奇怪、
but I always, always do it where I put it onto its own line
但我總是把它放在自己的行上
because the grid template areas
因為網格模板區域
tend to get a little bit complex,
會變得有點複雜、
and we're going to see that once we get to the media query,
一旦我們進入媒體查詢，就會發現這一點、
it's going to have a little bit more going.
就會有更多的內容。
And it's also kind of weird because it does all go in strings
這也有點奇怪，因為它確實都是以字串的形式出現的。
But I'm gonna write 1 here
但我要在這裡寫 1
and then actually gonna go on a new line and in quotations can be single or double quotations, three
然後換一行，引號可以是單引號或雙引號，3
and
和
five and
五
I always forget my semicolon at the end. So just don't forget after the last one
我總是忘記結尾的分號。所以不要忘了最後一個引號後面的分號
You do need a semicolon
你確實需要一個分號
and let's let's save and let's see what that's actually done because this has done something even though we don't see a difference yet and
讓我們儲存一下，看看到底做了什麼，因為這已經做了一些事情，儘管我們還沒看到有什麼不同。
And to be able to see it, once again,
為了能夠再次看到它、
we'll open up our visualization tools on my grid.
我們將開啟網格上的視覺化工具。
So we can open the grid here,
因此，我們可以在這裡開啟網格、
and I have line numbers enabled.
我啟用了行號。
So if you don't see the line areas,
所以，如果你沒有看到線條區域、
my area names are enabled.
我的區域名稱已啟用。
So it's within the Layout tab,
這就在 "佈局 "選項卡中、
this is in Chrome and in Firefox.
在 Chrome 瀏覽器和火狐瀏覽器中都是如此。
Chrome, it's these little, little tabs that show up here
Chrome 瀏覽器上顯示的是這些小標籤頁
whereas in Firefox they're really just in your face.
而在火狐瀏覽器中，它們就在你眼前。
So I like the in your face ones a little bit better.
所以，我更喜歡 "面對面 "的標籤頁。
And we can see we have one, two, three, four,
我們可以看到我們有 1、2、3、4、
and five at the bottom.
和底部的五個。
Now, what's the point of this?
現在，這有什麼意義呢？
Let's go down into my media query
讓我們進入媒體查詢
and here we're gonna write testDemonialGrid
這裡我們要寫 testDemonialGrid
and we're gonna say gridTemplateAreas
並寫上 gridTemplateAreas
and we're gonna redefine them.
並重新定義它們。
So let's come here.
讓我們到這裡來。
And what we're gonna say is we're gonna have...
我們要說的是...
We're gonna match the design for now.
我們現在要匹配設計。
So it's a one, one and five.
所以是1 1和5
And let's go back into Figma.
讓我們回到Figma裡
And so if you remember in the markup
如果你還記得在標記中
this is one, this is number two,
這是1，這是2
Then this is number three.
然後這是三號
This is number four and then this one is number five.
這是四號，然後這個是五號。
And again, draw things.
然後再畫一次
So we have five here and five here,
這裡是五，這裡是五、
four there, four here.
這裡是四，這裡是四
Let's make that four all in white
讓我們把四號都畫成白色
and then we have a one there and a one here.
然後這裡一個，這裡一個。
So we have area one,
這樣我們就有了一區、
one, two, five.
一、二、五
And then we come down to this next row.
然後我們來到下一排。
Three, four, four, five.
三、四、四、五
So I can write that
所以我可以寫
and I'd usually don't number it like this
我通常不會這樣編號
I actually give the meaningful names
實際上，我給出的是有意義的名字
but so that was
但這就是
three, four, five.
三 四 五
uh, four, four, or five?
呃，四，四，還是五？
Four, four, or five, and that was one, one,
四，四，還是五，那是一，一、
it wasn't one, one, five, one, one, two, five.
不是一 一 五 一 一 二 五
There we go, two, five, and when we look at here,
好了，二，五，再看這裡
what it did is it made one row for each of these.
它所做的就是為每一行都做了一個引號。
So every set of quotation marks is going to be a row
所以每組引號都是一行
and so here we just had one by itself,
所以這裡只有一個引號、
two by itself, three by itself.
二、三。
That's exactly what we see right now.
這正是我們現在所看到的。
One, two, three, just like we have one, two, three,
一、二、三，就像我們的一、二、三、
four, five here.
四、五
Every set of quotation marks here is the row
這裡的每組引號都是一行
and then within this row
然後在這一行中
I'm creating different columns and for each one of these columns. I'm giving them a name and so let's hit save and
我為每一列建立了不同的列。我給它們起了個名字，然後點選儲存
Look at that some magic happened, but you'll notice it's not using the area as well
看，一些神奇的事情發生了，但你會發現它並沒有使用區域
But here we can see I have 1 1 2
在這裡，我們可以看到 1 1 2
5 5 continues down here for goes across these two and three is here and we'll even notice it puts these like solid red
5 5 在這裡繼續向下，穿過這兩個區域，3 在這裡，我們甚至可以看到它把這些區域畫成了紅色的實線
Lines around the areas
線圍繞著這些區域
To highlight where they are in the visualization tools where is here like between 4 and 4 there's no solid red line
以突出它們在視覺化工具中的位置 4 和 4 之間沒有紅色實線
so it tries to help us show us where things are.
因此，它試圖幫助我們顯示事物的位置。
So that just means we need to use these grid areas
這就意味著我們需要使用這些網格區域
and again, is this more set-up.
再次強調，這是更多的設定。
Yes, it definitely is more set up
是的，這肯定是更多的設定
and I just find it works so well
而且我發現
once you've taken the time to do this.
一旦你花時間做了這些。
I'm gonna use this because of the way the layout is
我要用這個，因為它的佈局方式是
with the nth-child Selector.
nth-child 選擇器。
A lot of the time I'm doing this on a component
很多時候，我都是在一個元件上這樣做的
that has like, you know, it might be your name,
可能是你的名字、
your name, your role, a description, an image.
你的名字、角色、描述、圖片。
So you can choose those selectors
所以你可以選擇這些選擇器
that you've already made in those classes
你已經在這些類中
and be applying all of that to those.
並將所有這些應用到這些類中。
But what we'll do is we'll come here.
但我們要做的是來到這裡。
We'll say, and I'll set this up really fast.
我們會說，我會快速設定這個。
So we'll fast forward for a second.
我們先快進一下。
Okay, so I've set up my nth-child selectors
好的，我已經設定了 nth-child 選擇器
and each one is my testimonie nth-child,
每一個都是我的第 n 個子節點、
so my first child, second child, third child,
我的第一個孩子、第二個孩子、第三個孩子、
fourth child, and my fifth child,
第四個孩子，還有我的第五個孩子、
and then to place something on a grid area
然後在網格區域中放置東西
you just want to come in and say
你只需要進來說
what grid area they should be living on.
他們應該生活在哪個網格區域。
So my first one should be living on grid area one,
所以，我的第一個孩子應該住在第一網格區域、
and you'll notice here
你會注意到
here, it's not in quotation marks and this is something I think gets some people caught
在這裡，它沒有用引號，我想這一點會讓一些人措手不及。
off guard.
措手不及。
Here they're using one, here we're setting everything in like a string type of thing.
在這裡，他們使用的是引號，而在這裡，我們把所有內容都設定成字串的形式。
It's in quotation marks, here you don't use quotation marks.
這裡用引號，這裡不用引號。
Just to be aware of that and then we can do a two and then we can use a three and we can
注意這一點，然後我們可以使用二，然後我們可以使用三，然後我們可以
put a four and then we can set a five here.
然後在這裡設定一個五。
Hit save and my layout comes together there's one issue with it but look at that.
點選儲存，我的佈局就完成了。
it's come together and then we can shrink that down
我們可以把它縮小
and it pops over and then comes back and what I really like about grid areas
它就會跳出來，然後再回來，我很喜歡網格區域的一點是
is, check this out! Let's take this guy, copy them and paste
是，看看這個！讓我們把這個傢伙複製貼上上去
them. And maybe we do this at 30 rem instead
然後貼上 也許我們可以在 30 英里處這樣做
so we're going to create two different ones
所以我們要建立兩個不同的
and we do one one um let's just do one one then we'll do a
我們先做一個，再做一個
two five a three five
二 五 三 五
And then a four, five, and hit save.
然後是四、五，點選儲存。
And so now let's go all the way down.
現在我們一路向下
They all stack on top of each other,
它們會疊加在一起、
just like we had it.
就像我們之前做的那樣
Then I come to here and I get my one, two,
然後我來到這裡 我得到了我的一 二
five, three, five, four five.
五、三、五、四、五
Doesn't really work with this layout,
這樣的佈局不太合適、
but you can see it's going.
但你可以看到它的走向
Or so maybe we do four, four then across the bottom.
或者，我們可以做四，四，然後穿過底部。
And then we hit that.
然後我們打那個。
There we go.
就這樣
So we have this layout like that
這樣我們就有了這樣的佈局
and then we do a larger layout
然後我們做一個更大的佈局
and then it goes that way.
然後往那邊走
and you can just change the layout how you need to
您可以根據需要更改佈局
at different screen sizes so easily.
在不同的螢幕尺寸下改變佈局。
And what I really love with this
我最喜歡的是
is I'm only worried about the parent.
是我只擔心父版。
I don't have to do anything on the children.
我不必為孩子們做任何事情。
This is the children.
這就是子代。
I set the grid area they live on.
我可以設定它們所在的網格區域。
I never have to worry about it again,
我再也不用擔心了
which is just so magical.
這真是太神奇了
And for this to be working at this stage,
在這個階段，我所做的一切
all I've done is display grid, a gap
我所做的就是顯示網格、間隙
and a grid template areas,
和網格模板區域、
and then I'm just redefining the grid template areas
然後重新定義網格模板區域
for each one.
為每個網格重新定義網格模板區域。
And with the visualization and seeing,
然後就可以看到視覺化效果了、
Oh, I have a grid area here. I have the grid area here
哦，我這裡有一個網格區域。這裡有網格區域
I find this
我發現這
So easy, and so simple to work this way, and I don't even need spans because I'm saying that my one
我甚至不需要跨度，因為我說的是我的那一個。
Let's go find him my grid area one
我們去找我的一格區域吧
Your living on grid area one and grid area one is going across two different columns
你住在網格區域一，而網格區域一要穿過兩個不同的列
So it's going to span those two columns. It's wonderful. Now, you might have noticed we ran into that issue
所以它要跨越這兩列。太棒了 現在，你可能已經注意到我們遇到的問題了
I talked about when I deleted my display
當我刪除我的顯示時
When I deleted the grid template
當我刪除網格模板
columns that I'd originally set up with that repeat syntax,
列時，就遇到了我說過的問題、
where the columns are different sizes.
列的大小不同。
This one's really small and this one's bigger,
這一列非常小，這一列比較大、
just because of the way the content is distributed
只是因為內容的分佈方式
and it's doing its automatic thing to make it work.
而自動執行的。
Which is cool, and it may be that's happy
這很酷，也許這很快樂
and maybe this is exactly what you need.
也許這正是你所需要的。
But if you do wanna ensure that you have
但如果你想確保你的
columns that are always the same size
列的大小始終一致
and you're not actually setting up any columns,
而實際上你並沒有設定任何列、
we can do this in one spot,
我們可以在一個地方實現這一點、
and then never have to worry about it,
然後就再也不用擔心了、
which is coming here and saying grid auto columns.
這就是來這裡說的網格自動列。
Because these columns are automatically being generated
因為這些列是自動生成的
based on my grid template areas,
基於我的網格模板區域、
so it's grid auto columns,
所以是網格自動列、
and then you say what size you want them to be.
然後，你就可以說出想要它們的大小了。
And that means any automatically generated column,
這意味著任何自動生成的列、
and you can do the same for rows.
行也是一樣。
Any automatically generated column will be 1FR.
任何自動生成的列都將是 1FR。
So if I hit save, now each column is the same size,
如果我點選儲存，現在每一列的大小都一樣了、
we get nice even columns,
我們就能得到均勻的列了、
and the layout becomes a little bit more balanced.
這樣佈局就會更平衡一些。
And if you really like this grid template areas approach of working,
如果你非常喜歡這種網格模板區域的工作方法，那麼你就可以使用這種方法、
but you want to see it with an example where I'm not using nth child and I'm
但又想看一個例子，我沒有使用第 n 個子網格，而是
actually doing it in a bit more realistic of a situation perhaps there's a
實際上是在更現實的情況下進行的，也許有一個
video here for viewing pleasure that you can check out.
影片供你欣賞。
Right,
好的、
I dive a lot deeper into that and with that a really big thank you to all of my
在此，我非常感謝我所有的
patrons for their monthly support.
贊助人的每月支援。
I can't do it without you guys and until next time,
沒有你們我做不到，下次再見、
don't forget to make your part of the Internet just a little bit more awesome.
別忘了讓你們的網際網路變得更棒。